welcome back
today we are going to work on a water purification plant
but let's start from the beginning
the first task we have to do is scan a bucket of water
as usual
that will produce the research results required to craft something in an assembly line
which in this case
is the controller for the main structure of our water purification plant
and the only thing left for completing its structure is some water
once we finish the structure
we can turn it on and verify that
it is doing nothing every two minutes
it is also not using any power
even though we are feeding it 16 amps of LuV
but that is normal
because that is just the center of our waterline
to do something it needs some modules installed
and the first modulant step of the line
is the clarifier purification unit
after building its structure
we link it to our main block using a data stick
then after turning it on
we have to wait for the main block to start a new cycle
since they will work in sync
and with that
we are now starting the water purification process with some filtering
and we are going to send our purified water grade 1
to AE2 for better management
the first usage we are going to have for that
is to scan one cell of the fluid
that will unlock the crafting recipe for the next step
the Ozonation Purification Unit
and it was then that we noticed something
crafting the carbon filters for the previous filtering process
clogged our large chemical reactor
and when a multi block can't keep up with the crafting
we switch to a mega block
the Mega Chemical Reactor has perfect overclocking
does 256 parallel by default
but can also do tasks in batch mode
once the ozonation unit is ready
we can start optimizing its working
to have a decent yield
we have to input as much ozone possible
but we must not exceed the explosion threshold
and it looks like the ZPM input hatch has exactly the capacity
to reach the perfect working conditions
once everything is ready
we link the structure
and wait for the start of the next cycle
and I wonder how we will manage the ozone
when we will do parallels with that structure
and this was the second grade of water
the next step is the flocculation
however
it looks like our flocculation plant is stuck due to our EBFs
and if we turn on our mega blast furnace
the weather becomes kind of of foggy
to fix the weather
we have built a tier 3 air filter
and after upgrading it and adding some filters
we managed to clean up all of that pollution
or maybe that was just because our blast furnace finished the queue materials
which means that we can go back to our waterline
because we are ready to do some flocculation
the main gimmick of that stage
is that we have to input the flocculant fluid polyaluminium Chloride in an amount multiple of 100 K
we can easily accomplish that by using a bunch of covers
a fluid regulator that will output exactly 100k fluid
slightly more than 10 times every 2 minutes
however
this fluid regulator will have to stop working
when the outputted fluid is not consumed
or when there isn't enough fluid ready to be moved
and with that
we can link it to our water plant to test it out
and after two minutes
we got our flocculated water
and we also got a lot of waste byproduct
but this waste is super useful
since it contains all of the chlorine and aluminium we used for the flocculent
thus we are going to recycle it in place
however
that is giving off diluted hydrochloric acid
which we have to concentrate
but since it looks like our small distillation tower can't keep up with the task
as usual
we have to build a Mega one
and even the mega distillation tower with 16 IV amps
can barely keep up with the job
anyways now that we have the flocculated water
we can finally cut our europium wafers
which with the help of more flocculated water
can be used to obtain the integrated nano power circuit
that we can use to finally obtain ZPM energy hatches
to upgrade our multi blocks
but the first thing we will do with those
is a pH neutralization purification plant
to keep our waterline going
and there we have the structure built
this time we have to carefully insert some chemicals
to correct the acidity of the water
to do so
we are going to set the plant acidity sensors to the limit of the acceptable range
those sensors will slowly input either sodium hydroxide or hydrochloric acid
and here we can see the sensors
slowly overcorrecting the acidity
and then making it go back to the correct value
this pH corrected water will do the same recipes of the flocculated one
but it will half the processing time
to get the next water purification plant
we need UV parts
which require americium
and to make americium
we need a fusion reactor Mark 2
which we can quickly craft
after adding it to our fusion tunnel
we start making americium right away
and that process is incredibly slow
it takes 40 seconds for each ingot
and we need 48 ingots for each UV motor
but there is something even nastier in those motors
neutronium
that stuff other than a lot of time
also takes an awful lot of energy to be processed
but since we don't need much of that material
our volcanoes managed to complete the task
going back to our waterline
now that we have UV parts
the next expensive component for the purification plant tier 5
is the UV energy hatch
the main issue here is that
we are going to need a bunch of UV assemblers to craft it
usually we would do many assemblers
but those contains a lot of motors
but it now takes about half an hour for each motor
however with the ZPM Energy Hatch
we unlocked the Large Scale Auto-Assembler v1.01
which is the only assembler capable of overvolting
meaning that by using two ZPM Energy hatches
we can do UV recipes inside it
and with that
the only thing separating us from our tier 5 water is bedrockium
to get bedrockium
we have to assemble a block of diamonds with a lot of compressed cobblestone
and the main issue here is that
we are going to need a lot of explosives to compress that much of it
right now we are making explosives using oil
but we have nowhere close to the required amounts
for a decent amount of bedrockium
we are already processing all the toluene we can get out of oil
but we need a better source now
and it looks like wood tar is the best option
which also gives some nice byproducts
however
the only good farm that doesn't requires us to do crops
require nether stars
so far
we have been collecting those from withers
but I think it is time to find a better source
such as mining nether Star ores on tier 7 planets
so we quickly crafted tier 6 rocket
just to collect the rocket plan on Proteus
then while working on the tier 7 rocket
we had an unexpected issue
something went wrong in our nuclear plant
we run out of coolant cells
and our reactor is so close to blowing up
that we must not touch the heat capacity plates
not to mention random nearby blocks turning into fire
and the bottleneck seems to be our vacuum freezer
which couldn't even run at full capacity
due to lack of inventory space
we have now used an AE2 storage to manage the cells
but it still can't keep up with the extra heat
caused by all the upgrades we did lately
however
since today episode is about water
we are not going to expand our power production
we just throttle everything based on what our mega vacuum freezer can keep up with
and after a long time of cooking
we find out that
what is separating us from our next rocket is
once again nether Stars
since our wither farm isn't working properly
we go with the old way
and after farming wither for the hopelessly last time
we finally craft our new rocket
which took a heavy toll on our TNT supply
and we barely managed to make it to the rocket
however this time crafting the rocket was not enough
we also had to do some quick upgrades to our base
so that we could produce its fuel
and our destination is Haumea
where we can find the Nether Star Ore
we quickly drop down a ore drilling plant
and then head back
where we will already find enough nether star for crafting a void miner
but the first thing we are going to do with those
is a grav suit
the advanced nano cast plate made us fly in quite fast
but the Grav suit is on a different level
and that was enough playing around
what we wanted was just to get a tree farm
so that we could make some more toluene
to explode more bedrockium
so that we can get our tier 5 water purification plant
and after compressing a lot of cobblestone
there we have it
this huge multi block
is going to do some heat cycles to the water
and obliterate anything inside the water
as usual
it gets a little harder to automate than the previous step
this time we are going to use Steve's factory manager to do the automation
to cycle a temperature
we are going to check every second
if the plant hatches are empty
if they contain no fluids
then
we will check if the last input was coolant or helium
to decide what to insert next
to keep track of the last phase
we are going to move a piece of cobblestone between two chests
finally after inserting the correct fluid
we also move the cobblestone to Mark the next loop
every loop consists of 100 liters of plasma
that will take 10 seconds to heat up the water to 1000 Kelvin degrees
then with two buckets of super coolant
we cool it down to 0 Kelvin in 20 seconds
each loops takes 30 seconds
and the water cycle lasts 2 minutes
meaning that we can fit 4 heating loops in each water iteration
and that's a waste
since we would get 99 percent success chance with just 3 loops
the output is extreme temperature treated water
which we will probably want to pass through the next machine
however
the next water purification plants requires some UV motors
and right now we are nowhere close to making that much americium
other than the crafting time
the issue is also that we are making it with lutetium
which we are making as byproduct of waste thorium fuel
there is a cheaper and faster way of making it
but that requires a fusion reactor MK 3
so we shall use our americium to craft that one instead
but while we can easily make the casings
the controller requires a UV field generator
which requires wetware circuits
that are a whole new rabbit hole
so this episode is ending here
but don't worry
there are three more steps that we can do to improve our waterline
but we will see them when we will need them
bye bye
欢迎回来！
今天我们要开始净化水线
先从头开始
第一个目标是扫描一桶水
像往常一样
这将产出装配线需要的研究结果
在这里
则是净化水的主体净水厂
现在只剩下倒水就能完成结构
一旦完成结构
我们可以开启它试试
现在每两分钟啥也不输出
即使给它输入了 16A LuV
也不会消耗一点电
但那很正常
因为那只是净化水线的中心
想开始净化的话，需要安装一些模块
而水线的第一个模块
是澄清净化单元
在构建其结构后
我们使用闪存将其连接到主结构
开机后
要等待一次新的循环
因为它们将同步工作
有了这个
我们将开始用过滤处理出一些净化水
将一级净化水发送到 AE
来更好的管理
它第一个用处
便是扫描一个一级净化水单元
这将开启下一步的制作配方
臭氧净化装置
就在那时，我们注意到一些事情
为之前的过滤过程制作活性炭过滤器
把大化反给堵住了
当普通的大化反无法跟上进度时
我们求助于巨化反
巨化反仍具有无损超频的机制
默认 256 并行
但也可以在批处理模式下完成任务
一旦臭氧装置准备好
我们可以开始配置它的工作
为获得可观的产量
我们必须输入尽可能多的臭氧
但不能超过爆炸阈值
而一个 ZPM 输入仓则正好
能达到完美的工作条件
一旦一切准备就绪
连接结构
并等待下一个周期开始
我想知道当使用并行处理时
臭氧问题该如何处理呢
这是二级净化水
下一步是絮凝
然而
看起来我们的絮凝装置因为高炉卡住了
如果开启巨高炉
天气变得有点雾蒙蒙的
为了改善环境
我们做了台三级空气过滤器
升级并添加一些滤网
我们清除了所有的污染
或者那只是因为我们的高炉完成了处理
这意味着可以回到净化水线
而我们也准备好了絮凝装置
这个阶段的主要难点
必须每次精准输入100kL絮凝剂，聚氯化铝
用一堆覆盖板便可以很轻易达成这个目标
一个可以精准输出 100kL 流体的校准器
将在每两分钟工作略多于 10 次
然而
这个流体校准器将强制停止工作
当输出的液体没有被消耗
或者没有足够的液体可以转移
有了这个
我们将其连接到水厂进行测试
两分钟后
我们得到了絮凝水
我们也得到了很多絮凝废液
但这副产超级有用
因为它含有我们用于絮凝剂的所有氯和铝
因此，我们将就地回收它
然而
它会产出稀盐酸
我们需要浓缩它
但小蒸馏塔的速度似乎跟不上
像往常一样
我们建造一个巨型蒸馏塔
甚至是输入了 16A IV 的巨蒸馏
都几乎跟不上速度
不管怎样，现在我们有絮凝水了。
终于可以切开铕晶圆了
在更多絮凝水的帮助下
铕晶圆可以变成集成纳米功率晶圆
最终做出 ZPM 能源仓
来升级我们的多方块结构
但是我们要做的第一件事就是
pH 中和净化厂
来继续推进净化水线
在那里建造好结构
这次我们要小心地输入一些化学物质
来调节水的酸碱度
为此
我们将把 pH 传感器仓设置到可接受范围的极限
这些传感器会慢慢输入氢氧化钠或者盐酸
在这里我们可以看到传感器
正在慢慢地校正酸度
使它回到正确的值
pH 校正水能做的配方与絮凝水相同
但用它处理切割配方会减少一半的时间
为了得到下一个净水厂
我们需要UV零件
它们需要用到镅
而想制造镅
我们需要一个核聚变反应堆 MKⅡ
而我们已经可以轻松做出
把它加入核聚变阵列后
我们马上就开始制造镅
这个过程非常缓慢
每个锭所需时间为 40 秒
每个 UV 马达需要 48 个锭
但制作马达需要更恶心人的材料
中子
它不仅需要大量时间
还需要大量的能量来处理
但因为我们不需要太多材料
我们的炽焰高炉勉强完成了任务
回到净化水线
现在我们有了 UV 部件
下一个五级净化水厂所需的昂贵材料
是 UV 能源仓
现在主要问题是
我们将需要一堆 UV 组装机来制作它
通常我们会做很多组装机
但这要制作大量马达
而现在每做一个都需要半小时
不过有了 ZPM 能源仓
我们解锁了大规模自动组装器v1.01
这是唯一可以升压的组装机了
这意味着通过使用两个 ZPM 能源仓
便可以解锁 UV 配方
有了这个
唯一把我们和五级水隔开的就是基岩锭
想得到基岩锭
必须把大量压缩圆石与钻石块组装在一起
这里的主要问题是
我们需要大量的爆炸物来进行压缩
而我们正在用石油制造炸药
但离所需的量还远着呢
对于可观数量的基岩锭
我们已经用完了所有可能从石油中提取的甲苯
但我们现在需要更好的来源
看起来木焦油是最好的选择
副产品也很不错
然而
唯一不需要我们种庄稼的好农场
需要下界之星
到目前为止
我们都是通过杀凋零获得它
是时候找个更好的来源了
比如在 T7 星球上开采下界之星矿
所以我们很快制作了 T6 火箭
这只是为了收集海卫八上的火箭图纸
然而在建造 T7 火箭时
我们遇到了一个意想不到的问题
核电站出了点问题
冷却单元用完了
我们的反应堆就快爆炸了
我们绝不能碰热容量板
更别提附近的方块在起火
瓶颈似乎是我们的冰箱
由于库存空间不足
它甚至不能满负荷运行
我们现在使用 AE 存储来管理单元
但它仍然跟不上核电的发热
因为我们最近升级了核电
然而
这一集是关于净化水的
我们不打算扩大电力生产
只是依照巨冰箱能跟上的速度来调整所有东西
经过长时间的烧制
我们发现
将我们与下一个火箭分隔开来的
又是下界之星
由于凋零农场不能正确工作
我们走老路
在痛苦中杀死最后一只凋零
我们终于造出了新火箭
而这对我们 TNT 供应造成了巨大的负担
但我们还是勉强造出了火箭
然而，仅仅制造出火箭是不够的
我们需要对基地进行一些快速升级
来生产火箭的燃料
我们的目的地是妊神星
在那里我们可以找到下界之星矿石
我们快速拍下一个采矿厂
然后回家
我们已经获得足够的材料来制作虚空采矿场了
但是要做的第一件事
是做一套重力装甲
先进的纳米铸板让我们飞得相当快
但重力胸甲纯纯降维打击
已经玩够了
我们想要的只是一个林场
由此制造更多的甲苯
来聚爆出更多的基岩锭
这样我们就做出 5 级净水厂了
压缩了很多圆石后
它来了
这个巨大的多方块结构
会对水进行一些热循环
来消灭水中的一切
像往常一样
它比上一步更难自动化
这次我们要用 SFM 来做自动化
对于一个温度循环
我们将每秒检查一次
输入仓是否是空的
如果它们不含液体
然后
我们会检查最后输入的是冷却剂还是氦等离子体
来决定下一步输入什么
为了跟踪最后输入
我们在两个箱子之间移动一块圆石
在输入正确的液体后
我们移动圆石来标记下一个循环
每次循环包括 100L 的等离子体
这将花 10 秒钟将水加热到 1000K
然后用两桶超级冷却剂
花 20 秒将其冷却到 0K
每个循环需要 30 秒
一次水线循环有 2 分钟
意味着我们可以在每次水循环中进行 4 次冷热循环
但这是一种浪费
因为我们只需 3 次循环就可以达到 99% 的成功率
水厂的输出是极温净化水
我们想让它进入下一台机器
然而
下一个净水厂需要一些 UV 马达
而现在离制造出那么多的镅还差得远
除了制作时间
问题还在于，我们用的是镥
这是从钍核废料出的副产品
有一种更便宜、更快的制镅法
但那需要聚变反应堆 MK III
所以我们先用镅来制造它
虽然我们可以很容易地制作外壳
但控制器需要一个 UV 力场发生器
而这需要湿件电路
那又是一个大坑
所以这一集到此结束
不过别担心
还有三个步骤可以改善我们的净化水线
我们会在需要的时候见到它们
拜拜
（俚语 down the rabbit hole）